Guide to the Internation Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 116 records, 1941-2007 IBT0046
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Local 116 records
1941-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0046
7.5 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.
Historical Note
Teamsters Local 116 served members in Fargo, North Dakota and neighboring Moorhead, Minnesota.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains two series; company files and general files. The latter includes material from Teamster-affiliated organizations outside of Local 116.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor and laboring classes; Labor unions; Labor; Labor unions -- North Dakota -- History -- 20th century; Trucking -- Law and Legislation; Public interest lobbying; Contracts; Collective labor agreements
- Company Files, 1941-2007; Series 1; 5.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains company files related to Teamsters Local 116 and other locals dating from 1941-2007. The files are mainly comprised of local union collective bargaining agreements and contract negotiation but also include correspondence, reports, handbooks and other miscellaneous material.
  - Adams, Inc., 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advance United Expressways, 1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aggregate Industries, 2001; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - All-American, Inc., 1976; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allied Systems Ltd., 2000; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Freight System, Inc. [1/3], 1979-1981; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Freight System, Inc. [2/3], 1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Freight System, Inc. [3/3], 1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Linen Supply Co., 1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Lutheran Homes, Inc., 1981; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ames Sand and Gravel, 2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anheuser-Busch, Inc., 1981; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Associated Grocers of Iowa, 1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barber Transportation Co., 1982-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Beatrice Foods Company, 1981; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bergseth Bros. Co., 1980-1983; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Big Red Grocery Company, 1976; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Black Hills Trucking Co., 1979; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - BN Transport Inc., 1972-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Briggs Transportation Co., 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Buckeye Gas Products Company, 1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cenex, Inc., 1996-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - C.F. Motor Freight, 1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City of East Grand Forks, MN, 1998; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - City of Glyndon, MN, 2006; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - City of Moorhead, MN, 1973-1994; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clark Equipment Company, 1974-1977; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Concrete Sectional Culvert Company, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Consolidated Freightways, 1964-1991; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Consumers Gas Co., 1947-1963; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cordell Motors, Inc., 1970-1971; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - County of Cass, ND, 1977-1981; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - County of Clay, ND, 1976-1980; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Crouse Cartage Company, 1999; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cummins Diesel Sales, Inc., 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cummins North Central, Inc., 1997-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Custom Fabrictors, Inc., 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dan Dugan Transport Company, 1976-1979; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dayton Warehousing Company, 1978-1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - D-S Beverages, Inc., 1983-2003; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Duncan Truck Service, Inc., 2000; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ed Phillips and Sons co., 1974-1978; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - E.W. Wylie, Inc., 1961-1981; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fairmont Foods Company, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fairway Foods, Inc. [1/2], 1969-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fairway Foods, Inc. [2/2], 1982-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Fargo Bottle Gas Company, 1946-1947; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fargo Freight Terminal and Warehouse Company, 1977; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fargo-Moorhead Automobile Dealers Association, 1977; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Farmers Union Central Exchange, Inc., 1973-1988; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The F.C. Hayer Company, 1981; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ferrellgas, Inc., 1988-2004; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Firestone Tire and Rubber Company, 1979; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fowler Transfer, Inc., 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Froedtert Malt Corporation, 1996; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gaffaney's Office Specialties Co., 1973; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gamble Robinson Company, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Garrett Freightlines, 1962-1970; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The General Electric Company, 1970; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Georgia-Pacific Corporation, 1973-1975; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Golden Harvest Foods, Inc., 1989-1990; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gray and Company, 1988; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hansen Distributing Company, 1981-1994; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hart Motor Express, Inc., 1961; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Home Gas Company, 1948-1970; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hvidsten Transport Company, 1952-1961; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hyman Freightways, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Independent School District #2164, 1999; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Indianhead Truck Line, Inc., 1982-1986; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 1426, 2002; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jamestown Grocery Company, 1979; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Keebler Company, 1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Kiefer Chevrolet Company, 1969; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kost Block Plant, 1973; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kraft Foods Global, Inc., 2005; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Laidlaw Transit Services, Inc., 1996; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lakeville Motor Express, 1999; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Luther Family Ford, 2004-2007; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Manchester Biscuit Company, 1947-1950; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - McKesson Corporation, 1975-1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Melroe Shop, 1977; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Mid-America Dairymen, Inc., 1978; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Midwest Excavating, 1999; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Midwest Motor Express, Inc., 1972-1995; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minneapolis Autombile Dealers' Association, 2006; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minot Federated Cooperative Shipping Association, 1976; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell Transport, Inc., 1967-1976; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mobility, Incorporated, 1972; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Modern Machine Works, 1970; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Montgomery Ward and Co., Inc., 1970-1985; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Moorhead Plastics, Inc., 1967; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Motorways 1980 Limited, 1987-1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Muscatell Chevrolet, Inc., 1969-1977; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Nabisco, Inc. [1/2], 1956-1980; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nabisco, Inc. [2/2], 1982-1999; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Nash-Finch Company, 1963-1971; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - North Dakota Concrete Products Company, 2000; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Northern Propane Gas Company [1/2], 1966-1979; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Northern Propane Gas Company [2/2], 1982-1984; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Northern School Supply Company, 1983; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Northern Tank Line, 1970-1985; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Northland Transfer, Inc., undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Old Dutch Foods, Inc., 1975-1992; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Overnite Express, Inc., 1977-1983; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Overvold Motors, Inc., 1969-1970; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pan-o-Gold Baking Company, 1978; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Penners International, Inc., 1992; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pepsi-Cola Company [1/3], 1956-1980; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pepsi-Cola Company [2/3], 1981-1993; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pepsi-Cola Company [3/3], 1994-2001; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Piggly Wiggly Northland Corp., 1957-1963; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Pillsbury Company, 1968-1985; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Quast Transfer, Inc., 1992; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Quiggle Transfer and Storage Company, 1955-1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Radford Company, 1974-1977; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ralph Thomas Chevrolet, 1981; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Red Owl Stores, Inc. [1/4], 1941-1962; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Red Owl Stores, Inc. [2/4], 1965-1976; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Red Owl Stores, Inc. [3/4], 1979-1982; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Red Owl Stores, Inc. [4/4], 1982-1985; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Red River Trails, Inc., 1992; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Reserve Supply Company, 1960-1985; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Roman Meal Milling Co., 1972-1979; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ruan Transport Corporation, 1977-1982; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rural Electric Supply Cooperative, 1973-1982; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - SCR Coaches, Inc., 1992-1996; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Silverline, Inc., 1971-1978; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Simon's, Inc., 1971-1984; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Smith, Follett and Crowl, 1959-1970; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Stewart Doyle, Inc., 1982; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Suburban Propane Gas Corporation, 1988-1996; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Swift and Company, 1959-1978; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Texgas Corporation, 1973-1982; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Thompson Bros. Mail Service, 1969; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Transport Inc., 1985-2004; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Truck Equipment Inc., 1970-1972; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Twin City Freight, Inc., 1977-1981; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - United Biscuit Company of America, 1962-1965; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Valley Ford, 1998-2000; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Wienckowski Truck Lines, Inc., 1976; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Wil-Rich Manufacturing Company, 1987; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Willitz Trucking, Inc., 1995-2001; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Wintz Freightways, Inc., 1995; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Wintz Parcel Drivers, Inc., 1989-1992; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Wisconsin Electric Cooperative, 1966-1972; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Wm. Collins, Inc., 1977; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Woodlant Transit, Inc., 1995; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - World Wide, Inc., 1982-1983; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - W.W. Wallwork, Inc. [1/2], 1977-1991; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - W.W. Wallwork, Inc. [2/2], 1994-2001; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- General Files, 1942-2003; Series 2; 2.5 Linear Feet
  Guide to the Internation Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 814 records, 1958-1994
  - The Associated General Contractors of America, 1979-1983; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Bankruptcy Proceedings, 1986; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, 1971-1990; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters Building Material and Construction Trades Division, 1982-1983; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Central States Area Agreements, 1982-2003; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Central States Joint Area Committee, undated; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Company Directories, 1971-1980; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Construction [1/5], 1973-1977; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Construction [2/5], 1977-1980; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Construction [3/5], 1988; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Construction [4/5], 1988; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Construction [5/5], 1988; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence [1/2], 1970-1978; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence [2/2], 1980-2003; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Frank E. Fitzsimmons, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The International Teamster Magazine, 1988 August - 1990 July; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - International Travel Arrangers, 1977; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Local 116 Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1985; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Local 116 Retiree Association, 1984; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Local Union By-Laws, 1977-1981; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Master Cement Agreements, 1970; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1970-1988; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Agreements, 1942-1996; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Freight Industry Negotiating Committee, 1990; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - National Master Automobile Transporters Agreement, 1991; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - National Master Freight Agreement Contract Guide, 1992; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - National Master Freight Agreement Riders, 1967-1985; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - National Pipe Line Agreement, 1971; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 1970-1995; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - North Dakota - South Dakota Tank Committee, 1985; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Over-the-Road Agreement Negotiation, 1969-1970; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets, 1978-1993; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, undated; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Public Employees, undated; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Reports, 1943-1992; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Strike Sanction / Out of Work Benefits Applications [1/2], 1959-1970; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Strike Sanction / Out of Work Benefits Applications [2/2], 1964-1981; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Teamsters 22nd International Convention, 1981; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Teamsters 24th International Convention [1/2], 1991; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Teamsters 24th International Convention [2/2], 1991; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Automotive and Petroleum Division, 1970; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Teamsters D.R.I.V.E., 1972-1984; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Teamsters Freight Bulletin, 1995; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Teamsters Joint Council 82, 1970; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Teamsters Legislative Report, 1984-1987; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Teamsters Local Union Directory, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Teamsters News Service, 1978-1984; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Training Certificates, 1966-1985; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - UCS Graphics Packets, 1991-1993; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - United States Capitol Flag Gift, 1979; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - United States Congress, 1970-1988; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Department of Transportation, 1972; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Western Conference Area Supplemental Agreements, 1991; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; Series 2 (Box 15, Folder 9)